Guide to the Stanford Lands Clippings and Ephemera Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Lands Clippings and Ephemera collection
1950-1967
SC0678
Stanford University
1 Linear feet
This collection consists of photocopied clippings, with a few press releases and other items, which were once in a series of scrapbooks. Due to their deteriorating condition, they were copied and arranged by topics.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of photocopied clippings, with a few press releases and other items, which were once in a series of scrapbooks. Due to their deteriorating condition, they were copied and arranged by topics. A few original clippings were retained for possible exhibit purposes. Subjects include flood control, freeways, housing, the industrial park, Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, the Stanford Shopping Center, the Stanford Barn (the old winery), the medical center, the Veterans Administration Hospital, and related events in Menlo Park and Palo Alto.
Access Terms
Stanford Linear Accelerator Center; Stanford Shopping Center.; Stanford University. Medical Center.; Veterans Administration Medical Center (Palo Alto, Calif.); Land use--Planning--California--Santa Clara County.; Palo Alto (Calif.); Stanford University--Planning.
Collection Contents
- Articles on Industry at Stanford, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Flood Control, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Flood Control, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Land Development Politics, [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Land Development Politics, [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Menlo Park Development, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Articles, [folder 1 of 2], 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Original News Clippings [kept for exhibit purposes], 1953-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Articles, [folder 2 of 2], 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Out of town articles on Stanford, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Palo Alto Development, [folder 1 of 2], 1953-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Palo Alto Development, [folder 2 of 2], 1953-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Palo Alto Recall and Election, [folder 1 of 2], 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Palo Alto Recall and Election, [folder 2 of 2], 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Palo Alto-Stanford Medical Center, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Serra Freeway, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Stanford Apartment Development, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Stanford Area News, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Stanford Barn and Winery, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Stanford Industrial Park, [folder 1 of 4], 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Stanford Industrial Park, [folder 2 of 4], 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stanford Industrial Park, [folder 3 of 4], 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Stanford Industrial Park, [folder 4 of 4], 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Stanford Land Development, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Stanford Land Development, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Stanford Land Development, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Stanford Land Development, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC), 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Stanford Professional Center, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Stanford Shopping Center, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Stanford Shopping Center, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Stanford Shopping Center, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Stanford University News, 1958-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Veterans Administration Hospital, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Willow Freeway, 1969-1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)